Finding Aids to Personal Papers and Special Collections in the VMFA Archives Lillian Thomas Pratt Personal Papers, 1901-1947 SC-07
VMFA Archives, Virginia Museum of Fine Arts
Lillian Thomas Pratt Personal Papers
1901-1947
VMFA Archives
Pratt, Lillian Thomas, 1876?
Schaffer, Alexander
Schaffer, Ray
Schaffer Collection
A La Vieille Russie (Firm)
Hammer Galleries
Virginia Museum of Fine Arts
SC-07
1 Linear Feet 2 boxes (15 folders), 1 oversize item and 1 binder
The collection documents the formation of the Lillian Thomas Pratt Collection of Fabergé decorative artworks at the Virginia Museum of Fine Arts. Bequeathed to the museum upon her death in 1947, Pratt's Fabergé collection consistently remains one of the highlights of the museum's permanent collection. Pratt purchased most of her Fabergé collection from the Schaffer Collection and Hammer Galleries, both of New York City, in the 1930s and 1940s. Comprised of correspondence, invoices, price tags, and detailed item descriptions, this collection illuminates Pratt's mind as a collector, as well as her relationship with one of her dealers, Alexander Schaffer.
Box SC-07 Box 1
Box SC-07 Box 2
Binder SC-07 Binder 1
Oversize SC-07 Oversize 1
Provenance
The collection was transferred over time to the VMFA Library in the 2000s by museum staff members Dr. David Park Curry, Curator of the Fabergé collection, David Bradley, Foundation Director, and Richard Woodward, Deputy Director for Architecture and Design. The estate tax information was given to Woodward from the Honorable John D. Butzner, Jr. in the 1970s. The bulk of the collection was accessioned into the VMFA Archives' collection in February 2011. In January 2015, an additional collection of original documents were transferred from the Curatorial files to the Pratt collection.
Access Restrictions
The collection is open for research.
Biographical Note
Two months after Lillian Thomas Pratt's death in June 1947, her stunning and expansive collection of Fabergé artworks were unexpectedly bequeathed to the Virginia Museum of Fine Arts. Thought to have been born in 1876 in Philadelphia, details of Pratt's life still remain sketchy and limited. By 1900, she was working as a stenographer at the Puget Sound Flouring Mill, and in 1917, married her second husband, John Lee Pratt, a self-made millionaire engineer and businessman with General Motors. By 1931, they had settled at Chatham Manor in John's native Virginia, and Pratt spent over a decade amassing a collection of over 500 items, eighty percent of which is Russian decorative art, mainly Fabergé.
Pratt began collecting while accompanying her husband on business trips to New York City, shopping in her spare time, and possibly becoming enchanted with the Hammer Galleries' "Russian Imperial Exhibit" at Lord and Taylor in the early 1930s. While the total amount she spent during that time is unknown, she spent $100,000 alone at New York City's Schaffer Collection. She simultaneously purchased items, including four of her five imperial Easter eggs, from the Hammer Galleries. Her collection includes not only the finest imperial eggs, but also miniature eggs, jewelry, framed photographs, boxes, handles, flowers, and animal figures, among many other types of objects. Whatever her collecting may have been (besides simply furnishing her new home), her fascination with Russian royalty was enduring, and has been shared with museum visitors for over 60 years.
(The above information was taken from "Fabergé: Virginia Museum of Fine Arts.")
Scope and Content Note
The collection's inclusive dates are 1901-1947, with the bulk of the material dating from 1933-1945. The collection is comprised of correspondence, invoices, price tags, item descriptions, exhibition labels, estate tax information and inventories, newspaper clippings, drawings and photographs.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into four series, and items are generally arranged chronologically within each series. Price tags are arranged numerically by item number. Items with no date are placed at the end at each series.
Series 1: Schaffer Collection, 1934-1947, undated
Series 2: Hammer Galleries, 1933-1945, undated
Series 3: Estate, 1932-1947, undated
Series 4: Clippings, 1932-1937, undated
Series 5: Museum Records, 1936-1947, undated
Related Materials - VMFA Library: Pratt's Personal Library
The Fall of the Romanoffs: How the Ex-Empress & Rasputine Caused the Russian Revolution, 1917
Confessions of the Czarina, 1918
Mother Dear: The Empress Marie of Russia and Her Times, 1926
The Tragic Bride: The Story of the Empress Alexandra of Russia, 1927
The Life and Tragedy of Alexandra Feodorovna, Empress of Russia, 1928
The Intimate Life of the Last Tzarina, 1928
The Real Romanovs, as Revealed by the Late Czar's Physician and His Son, 1931
Russia - My Home: An Intimate Record of Personal Experiences Before, During and After the Bolshevist Revolution, 1931
Education of a Princess: A Memoir, 1931
A Princess in Exile, 1932
Twice Seven, 1937
Russian Imperial Treasures: Collection of Lillian T. Pratt, undated
Related Materials - VMFA Library: Catalogs
Imperial Russian Easter Eggs Presented by Tsar Nikolai II, 1940
Handbook of the Lillian Thomas Pratt Collection: Russian Imperial Jewels, 1960
Fabergé: A Catalog of the Lillian Thomas Pratt Collection of Russian Imperial Jewels, 1976
Fabergé: Virginia Museum of Fine Arts, 1995
Fabergé Revealed: At the Virginia Museum of Fine Arts, 2011
Related Materials - VMFA Library: Video
Lillian Thomas Pratt's Fabergé: Shopping, Collecting, Remembering, 1996
Related Materials - VMFA Library: Exhibition Files
Selections from the Lillian Thomas Pratt Collection of Jewels, 1947
12th Anniversary Exhibition: The Pratt Collection of Jewels, 1948
Imperial Russian Easter Eggs, 1949
Imperial Russian Easter Eggs, 1950
Imperial Russian Easter Eggs, 1951
Imperial Russian Easter Eggs, 1952
Jewelry by Fabergé, 1953
Jewels by Fabergé, 1954
Fabergé in America and the Lillian Thomas Pratt Collection of Fabergé, 1996
Fabergé Revealed, 2011
Related Materials - VMFA Library: Subject Files
VMFA Collections: Decorative Arts: Metalwork: Fabergé
VMFA Donors: Pratt, John Lee and Lillian Thomas
VMFA Gallery Design: Fabergé
Related Materials - Library of Virginia
Virginia Museum of Fine Arts Director's Correspondence, 1936-1976 (Coll. No. 33863 and 44067)
Virginia Museum of Fine Arts Exhibition Files, 1936-1992 (Coll No. 31633, 32958, 33041, 33160, 34679, 36342, 36957 and 37636)
Lillian Thomas Pratt Collection.; Crown Jewels--Russia (Federation)--Art collections.; Jewelry--Russia (Federation)--Art collections.; Easter eggs--Russia (Federation)--Art collections.; Goldwork--Russia (Federation)--Art collections.; Art objects--Russia (Federation)--Art collections.; Fabergé, Peter Carl, 1846-1920; Fabergé (Firm)
- Series 1: Schaffer Collection, 1934-1947, undated; SC-07-01
  Box 1 (6 Folders and 1 Binder): This series is comprised of correspondence, invoices, price tags, and item descriptions that detail the purchases Pratt made from the Schaffer collection in the 1930s and 1940s. Correspondence between Alexander S. Schaffer, his wife Ray Schaffer, and Pratt discuss sales, payments, display cabinets, family matters, and books and articles he sent to Pratt about Russian history, war, and family matters. After 1944, some of the correspondence, invoices and item descriptions came from A La Vieille Russie, where Schaffer continued to deal in Russian art and antiquities after closing his own shop.
  The invoices are often annotated with check numbers as balances were paid off, and dates given often refer to the handwritten notes on the invoice detailing payment history. Similarly, price tags were often annotated with price reductions or alterations in the item’s description. Item descriptions are extremely detailed, and include the item number and often the date purchased. Many of the Schaffer descriptions are not dated, and while most of them can be cross-referenced with dates on the invoices, Schaffer often invoiced Pratt much later than the original purchase date, and in some cases, many years later. Finally, most of the item descriptions were annotated by museum staff at some point with VMFA accession numbers.
  The series is divided into five subseries: Series 1.1: Alexander Schaffer Correspondence, 1934-1947; Series 1.2: Ray Schaffer Correspondence, 1937-1947; Series 1.3: Invoices, 1934-1945, n.d.; Series 1.4: Price Tags, n.d.; Series 1.5: Item Descriptions, 1934-1945, n.d.
  - Series 1.1: Alexander Schaffer Correspondence, 1934-1947; SC-07-01.1
    - A. Schaffer to Pratt, Apr. 14, 1934 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 1)
    - A. Schaffer to Pratt, July 1, 1935 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 1)
    - A. Schaffer to Pratt, Nov. 19, 1935 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 1)
    - A. Schaffer to Pratt, June 2, 1936 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 1)
    - A. Schaffer to Pratt, June 8, 1936 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 1)
    - A. Schaffer to Pratt, Aug. 3, 1936 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 1)
    - A. Schaffer to Pratt, Aug. 14, 1936 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 1)
    - A. Schaffer to Pratt, Oct. 7, 1936 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 1)
    - A. Schaffer to Pratt, Oct. 10, 1936 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 1)
    - A. Schaffer to Pratt, Oct. 27, 1936 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 1)
    - A. Schaffer to Pratt, Nov. 21, 1936 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 1)
    - A. Schaffer to Pratt, Dec. 11, 1936 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 1)
    - A. Schaffer to Pratt, June 11, 1937 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 1)
    - A. Schaffer to Pratt, June 17, 1937 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 1)
    - A. Schaffer to Pratt, June 21, 1937 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 1)
    - A. Schaffer to Pratt, Aug. 6, 1937 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 1)
    - A. Schaffer to Pratt, Aug. 10, 1937 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 1)
    - A. Schaffer to Pratt, Sep. 1, 1937 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 1)
    - A. Schaffer to Pratt, Oct. 7, 1937 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 1)
    - A. Schaffer to Pratt, Oct. 11, 1937 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 1)
    - A. Schaffer to Pratt, Dec. 29, 1937 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 1)
    - A. Schaffer to Pratt, Apr. 15, 1938 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 1)
    - A. Schaffer to Pratt, Apr. 25, 1938 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 1)
    - A. Schaffer to Pratt, May 2, 1938 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 1)
    - A. Schaffer to Pratt, May 11, 1938 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 1)
    - A. Schaffer to Pratt, June 3, 1938 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 1)
    - A. Schaffer to Pratt, July 1, 1938 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 1)
    - A. Schaffer to Pratt, Aug. 1, 1938 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 1)
    - A. Schaffer to Pratt, Aug. 12, 1938 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 1)
    - A. Schaffer to Pratt, Oct. 4, 1938 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 1)
    - A. Schaffer to Pratt, Nov. 2, 1938 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 1)
    - A. Schaffer to Pratt, Apr. 3, 1939 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 1)
    - A. Schaffer to Pratt, Apr. 21, 1939 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 1)
    - A. Schaffer to Pratt, May 6, 1939 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 1)
    - A. Schaffer to Pratt, May 29, 1939 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 1)
    - A. Schaffer to Pratt, June 2, 1939 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 1)
    - A. Schaffer to Pratt, June 19, 1939 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 1)
    - A. Schaffer to Pratt, June 30, 1939 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 1)
    - A. Schaffer to Pratt, Aug. 1, 1939 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 1)
    - A. Schaffer to Pratt, Sep. 1, 1939 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 1)
    - A. Schaffer to Pratt (enclosure from Macomber and Company), Oct. 20, 1939 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 1)
    - A. Schaffer to Pratt, Oct. 31, 1939 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 1)
    - A. Schaffer to Pratt, Dec. 18, 1939 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 1)
    - A. Schaffer to Pratt, Dec. 29, 1939 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 1)
    - A. Schaffer to Pratt, Apr. 1, 1940 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 1)
    - A. Schaffer to Pratt, May 1, 1940 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 1)
    - A. Schaffer to Pratt, Sep. 3, 1940 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 1)
    - A. Schaffer to Pratt, Nov. 4, 1940 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 1)
    - A. Schaffer to Pratt, Dec. 11, 1940 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 1)
    - A. Schaffer to Pratt, Mar. 31, 1941 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 1)
    - A. Schaffer to Pratt, May 1, 1941 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 1)
    - A. Schaffer to Pratt, June 3, 1941 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 1)
    - A. Schaffer to Pratt, June 18, 1941 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 1)
    - A. Schaffer to Pratt, June 23, 1941 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 1)
    - A. Schaffer to Pratt, July 3, 1941 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 1)
    - A. Schaffer to Pratt, Aug. 4, 1941 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 1)
    - A. Schaffer to Pratt, Sep. 3, 1941 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 1)
    - A. Schaffer to Pratt, Oct. 2, 1941 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 1)
    - A. Schaffer to Pratt, Nov. 1, 1941 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 1)
    - A. Schaffer to Pratt (enclosure retirement notice), Nov. 13, 1941 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 1)
    - A. Schaffer to Pratt, Dec. 8, 1941 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 1)
    - A. Schaffer to Pratt, Dec. 8, 1941 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 1)
    - A. Schaffer to Pratt, Dec. 15, 1941 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 1)
    - A. Schaffer to Pratt, Dec. 30, 1941 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 1)
    - A. Schaffer to Pratt, Jan. 21, 1942 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 1)
    - A. Schaffer to Pratt, Nov. 21, 1945 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 1)
    - A. Schaffer to Pratt, June 4, 1946 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 1)
    - A. Schaffer to Pratt, May 6, 1947 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 1)
    - Original envelopes (9), undated (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 1)
  - Series 1.2: Ray Schaffer Correspondence, 1937-1947; SC-07-01.2
    - R. Schaffer to Pratt, July 1, 1937 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 2)
    - R. Schaffer to Pratt, Nov. 19, 1938 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 2)
    - R. Schaffer to Pratt, Feb. 3, 1942 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 2)
    - R. Schaffer to Pratt, Apr. 10, 1942 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 2)
    - R. Schaffer to Pratt, Apr. 24, 1942 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 2)
    - R. Schaffer to Pratt, June 3, 1942 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 2)
    - R. Schaffer to Pratt, July 5, 1942 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 2)
    - R. Schaffer to Pratt, Nov. 2, 1945 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 2)
    - Pratt to R. Schaffer, Dec. 4, 1945 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 2)
    - R. Schaffer to Pratt, Dec. 7, 1945 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 2)
    - R. Schaffer to Pratt, Mar. 13, 1947 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 2)
  - Series 1.3: Invoices, 1934-1945, undated; SC-07-01.3
    - 73/44, 38, 23, Mar. 1, 1934 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 3)
    - 70, D2, Apr. 2, 1934 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 3)
    - 86, 5, 36, June 4, 1934 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 3)
    - 461, 462, 463, 558, 181, 150, 309, Dec. 4, 1934 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 3)
    - 572, AS26, 438, 504, 571, 760, 774, 780, 598, 417, 419, 420, 421, 422, 423, 424, 425, 426, 427, 428, 429, 430, 431, 432, 435, 436, 437, 445, 447, 449, 450, 458, 459, 639, 673, 676, 779, 779A, June 1, 1935 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 3)
    - 110, 905, 909, 904, 911, 907, 908, 901, 893, 888, 912, 894, 1017, 1041, 1049, Nov. 1, 1935 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 3)
    - 1006, 972, 1043, 1176, Mar. 2, 1936 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 3)
    - 1088, 1097, 37, 991, 1306, 982, 987, 478, 482, 1166, 1035, 537, 476, 804, 1189, 1291, 986, May 1, 1936 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 3)
    - 533, 1317, 535, 1167, July 3, 1936 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 3)
    - 533, 1317, 535, 1167 Duplicate, July 3, 1936 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 3)
    - 1359, Dec. 10, 1936 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 3)
    - 1101, 539, 997, 509, 989, 481, 536, 480, 665, 538, 477, 479, 75, 1350, 1315, 1075, 1078, 1073, 1317, Feb. 1-Oct. 1, 1937 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 3)
    - 1597, 1537, 1562, 1575, 1578, 182, 1589, 1549, 1464, 1546, June 1, 1937 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 3)
    - G.3, G.5, G.8, G.13, G.14, G.16, 1556, 1573, 1576, 1580, 1661, 1736, 1737, 2237, 2238, Aug. 18, 1937 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 3)
    - 1479, 1524, 1543, 1735, 2247, 2278, 2281, Apr. 1-June 1, 1939 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 3)
    - "Vulture, frame, frame, egg, parrot," handwritten list with prices on Hotel McAlpin stationary, [Apr. 1-June 1, 1939] (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 3)
    - Rock crystal handle, June 16, 1939 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 3)
    - G.22, 1509, 1568, 1591, 2136, 2243, 1934, 1956, June 30-Sep. 1, 1939 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 3)
    - 1182, 778, 1183, 906, 1343, 1367, 1345, 1364, Oct. 2-Nov. 1, 1939 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 3)
    - 798, 1205, Nov. 1-Dec. 28, 1939 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 3)
    - One cabinet, complete, including packing and shipping, Dec. 26, 1939 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 3)
    - 2299, 2340, 2419, Dec. 28, 1939-Feb. 1, 1940 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 3)
    - 2322, 2323, 2326, Feb. 1-Mar. 1, 1940 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 3)
    - 2353, L-14, Gold stand, Apr. 1, 1940 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 3)
    - 2497, 2496, 2325, 2498, Mar. 1-June 1, 1940 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 3)
    - 2453, 2421, 1569, 1546, June 1-Aug. 1, 1940 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 3)
    - 1022, 2279, G.25, 1749, 2297, 2300, Sep. 3, 1940-Feb. 1, 1941 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 3)
    - 2692, 2691, Feb. 1, 1941 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 3)
    - 2445, 2454, 2455, 2456, 2460, 2465, 2470, 2472, 2457, 2461, 2467, 2474, 2464, 2468, Mar. 1-June 2, 1941 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 3)
    - 2445, 2454, 2455, 2456, 2460, 2465, 2470, 2472, 2457, 2461, 2467, 2474, 2464, 2468 Duplicate, Mar. 1-June 2, 1941 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 3)
    - Gold bracelet, lapis and gold necklace, turquoise necklace with credit attachments, Mar. 6, 1941 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 3)
    - 2821, June 24, 1941 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 3)
    - 2524, 93, July 1-Dec. 29, 1941 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 3)
    - 1326, Feb. 2, 1942-Dec. 1, 1944 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 3)
    - 1326 Duplicate, Feb. 2, 1942-Dec. 1, 1944 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 3)
    - X-1937, Oct. 23, 1944 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 3)
    - 1763, 2723, JZ-1, JZ-2, JZ-3, JZ-4, Dec. 30, 1944-Jan. 31, 1945 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 3)
    - 2786, Jan. 31-Apr. 2, 1945 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 3)
    - 2722, 2859, 2882, 2868, 2869, 2870, Apr. 2-June 1, 1945 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 3)
    - 2568, 2680, 1044, 2657, June 1-Sep. 1, 1945 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 3)
    - 2675, 2525, 2651, 1578, Star ruby ring, Sep. 1-Nov. 8, 1945 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 3)
    - 2433, 2891, Nov. 7, 1945 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 3)
    - X.2366, X.2367, X.2368, Nov. 21, 1945 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 3)
    - 92, undated (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 3)
    - 93, undated (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 3)
    - 1085, 980, 1167, undated (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 3)
    - 2373, undated (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 3)
    - 2512, undated (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 3)
    - 2881, undated (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 3)
    - "Handles," handwritten list with prices, undated (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 3)
    - Original envelope, undated (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 3)
  - Series 1.4: Price Tags, undated; SC-07-01.4
    - D2, undated (Binder SC-07 Binder 1)
    - G.3, undated (Binder SC-07 Binder 1)
    - G.5, undated (Binder SC-07 Binder 1)
    - G.8 (2 tags), undated (Binder SC-07 Binder 1)
    - G.13, undated (Binder SC-07 Binder 1)
    - G.14, undated (Binder SC-07 Binder 1)
    - G.16, undated (Binder SC-07 Binder 1)
    - 5, undated (Binder SC-07 Binder 1)
    - 23, undated (Binder SC-07 Binder 1)
    - 36, undated (Binder SC-07 Binder 1)
    - 38, undated (Binder SC-07 Binder 1)
    - 70, undated (Binder SC-07 Binder 1)
    - 73/44, undated (Binder SC-07 Binder 1)
    - 75.WM, undated (Binder SC-07 Binder 1)
    - 86, undated (Binder SC-07 Binder 1)
    - 93, undated (Binder SC-07 Binder 1)
    - 477, undated (Binder SC-07 Binder 1)
    - 479, undated (Binder SC-07 Binder 1)
    - 480, undated (Binder SC-07 Binder 1)
    - 481, undated (Binder SC-07 Binder 1)
    - 509, undated (Binder SC-07 Binder 1)
    - 534, undated (Binder SC-07 Binder 1)
    - 536, undated (Binder SC-07 Binder 1)
    - 538, undated (Binder SC-07 Binder 1)
    - 539, undated (Binder SC-07 Binder 1)
    - 665, undated (Binder SC-07 Binder 1)
    - 989, undated (Binder SC-07 Binder 1)
    - 997, undated (Binder SC-07 Binder 1)
    - 1073, undated (Binder SC-07 Binder 1)
    - 1075, undated (Binder SC-07 Binder 1)
    - 1078, undated (Binder SC-07 Binder 1)
    - 1101, undated (Binder SC-07 Binder 1)
    - 1315, undated (Binder SC-07 Binder 1)
    - 1350, undated (Binder SC-07 Binder 1)
    - 1556, undated (Binder SC-07 Binder 1)
    - 1573, undated (Binder SC-07 Binder 1)
    - 1576, undated (Binder SC-07 Binder 1)
    - 1580, undated (Binder SC-07 Binder 1)
    - 1591, undated (Binder SC-07 Binder 1)
    - 1661, undated (Binder SC-07 Binder 1)
    - 1736, undated (Binder SC-07 Binder 1)
    - 1737, undated (Binder SC-07 Binder 1)
    - 2237, undated (Binder SC-07 Binder 1)
    - 2238, undated (Binder SC-07 Binder 1)
    - "Miniature gold and platinum charm in the form of a bulldog...", undated (Binder SC-07 Binder 1)
    - Original envelope, undated (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 4)
  - Series 1.5: Item Descriptions, 1934-1945, undated; SC-07-01.5
    - 572, Jan. 1, 1934 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 5)
    - "A most unusual topaz brooch…", Jan. 1, 1934 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 5)
    - 23, Mar. 1, 1934 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 5)
    - 23 Duplicate, Mar. 1, 1934 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 5)
    - 38, Mar. 1, 1934 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 5)
    - 73/44, Mar. 1, 1934 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 5)
    - 315, Easter [Apr. 1], 1934 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 5)
    - 70, Apr. 2, 1934 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 5)
    - D2, Apr. 2, 1934 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 5)
    - 86, Apr. 30, 1934 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 5)
    - 5, June 4, 1934 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 5)
    - 36, June 4, 1934 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 5)
    - 461, July 28, 1934 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 5)
    - 462, July 28, 1934 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 5)
    - 463, July 28, 1934 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 5)
    - 558, Sep. 28, 1934 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 5)
    - 150, Dec. 3, 1934 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 5)
    - 309, Dec. 3, 1934 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 5)
    - 597, Christmas [Dec. 25], 1934 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 5)
    - 504, Jan. 2, 1935 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 5)
    - 438, Feb. 26, 1935 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 5)
    - 571, Mar. 25, 1935 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 5)
    - 760, Mar. 25, 1935 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 5)
    - 774, Mar. 25, 1935 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 5)
    - 780, Mar. 25, 1935 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 5)
    - 818, Easter [Apr. 21], 1935 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 5)
    - 417, 419, 420, 421, 639, May 2, 1935 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 5)
    - 422, 423, 424, 445, 447, May 2, 1935 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 5)
    - 425, 426, 427, 428, 429, May 2, 1935 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 5)
    - 430, 431, 432, 435, 436, May 2, 1935 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 5)
    - 437, 458, 459, 673, 676, May 2, 1935 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 5)
    - 449, 450, 779, 779A, May 2, 1935 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 5)
    - 110, July 27, 1935 (Box SC-07 Box 1, Folder Folder 5)